i'm alive welcome to our whatever number
this is board meeting we've been talking
for the last few weeks doing the
foundational documents collective
foundational documents ourselves going
through values admission
vision and um although we came up with a
fairly good
concrete what those things are in bold
in the foundational document um
the talking it through helps and then
when we go on to the currencies we know
that
those things will change based on what
we come up with during
or we're doing the rest and we have
raymond here who joined us a couple
weeks ago as well
uh the person who's foundational is the
person who created the foundational
documents the protocol not love
the how we do these foundational
documents
here to help through that process so
that's awesome and bentley has just
moved so he's not on camera today
but we'll be joining as well
so where we go from here so
uh raymond do you have our foundational
agreement the one that's in it's in the
private chat on the side
that's when we've been working through
so you can see we've kept in gray
all of the things we kind of went
through and then the one that we have
currently is
is the one kind of more involved the
world so our vision is a world where
abundant resources are available to pro
omni win projects our mission
expanding the adjacent possible we have
community mentorship camaraderie
relationships and piragi
i said that right knowledge commons
funding and money and then shared
resources
if i we spent a while defining what omni
win was who does it all include and what
does wind mean and what does omni mean
that's important values are although i
if i don't know we kind of had a two two
different
if you were here if you weren't here
raymond we're like if you're not here
we'll go we'll see what we can do
through currency
but you're here you're more of an expert
in the currencies that are
not the regular currency yeah
cool well um
i in reading this i mean just the
initial feedback as i
which which is going to be it's not just
feedback of the fake
sake of saying it it's feedback because
it's going to be useful
in the other sections as you were
mentioning to have the mission
to i still don't know what you actually
plan to do
just reading what i see here
[Music]
yeah i will say with the mission being
expanding the adjacent possible
personally i find that too vague because
that's really just saying take the next
step
but the next step in what just always
take the next step yeah yeah
it's like what are you actually going no
that wasn't our mission statement was it
i don't think it's in that section i
don't think we have a
statement we just like started a mission
list like uh i'm not sure how i don't
think like we
no we see the vision the vision
statement explains it because
yeah so
right so like like how are you going to
make abundant resources available to pro
omni when projects would be what you
want to
answer in the mission as concisely as
possible
so go ahead
sorry it was like so like community i
assume you mean build community
by mentoring
camaraderie and relationships using
pureology or something like that maybe
that's what's actually maybe it's pretty
close
i can't see the document right now but
in there
we said you know that we were going to
have
um uh
you know that we were gonna have shared
resources we were gonna have
a uh knowledge base we were gonna have
mentoring so where's that sentence
there well that's the thing they're not
sentences i guess that's what's throwing
me
i think the one of those sentences in
there has that
yes that's yeah that i thought
highlighted
but apparently we changed it
so i think we had sentences and that was
i think
oh i think that may have been too
cleaned up um yeah we definitely had
some sentences but i think like they
weren't
uh i wanna see if i still have to have
them here
no um yes i think we had went back
and sort of like tried to come up with
what exactly are we trying to do like
what's our role
in in providing a world where abundant
resources are available to pro omni and
projects
so
that that's my understanding but of
course be afraid
i think that people disagree i mean that
is
why we had it as so complex and then
down to expanding the adjacent possible
is there's like what we would love to do
if we had all the funding and all the
people
but we're not doing that because we
don't have all the people in all the
funding so it's like
keep looking at the adjacent possible of
creating those omni-win solutions which
we're already doing we're already
meeting and talking about our projects
and how do we just keep looking for the
next piece of that
is like how i read this and after a few
weeks
but it should be actually readable
probably not
everyone reads something differently
into it but there isn't a
you know direct road map on how to get
there because it's going to change as we
go
it's going to be what is the next
adjacent possible that's going to
um help us get to the next level of our
various individual projects
cool those words sound important
they should be in there
i think
and that is i mean we have down below
here which i think was kind of our
mission the expanding the adjacent
possible was like the part at the bottom
and that was to me like our entire
mission but it's not how does the next
person come on
and understand all of that that we've
put you know weeks into
it's like expanding is impossible
here's your first iteration right
of the person coming in
yeah um
so that's that so this is what you meant
to build community that provides
mentorship to build camaraderie and
relationships using
pure pirage that's definitely
more cohesive to me except that i don't
know what you're getting chips
yeah i just don't think that that's the
primary purpose yeah and i think like
those are all different things like peer
gy is to learn from your peers and
mentorship is to learn you know from
sort of i guess that's more a a
one-directional-ish
and the camaraderie is just like sort of
the relationships and networking
so i think mentorship and peer golgi you
could say are similar
but camaraderie is just its own its own
thing or the
the relationships or networking so maybe
it's just those two
maybe it's paragony because i think you
could say that mentorship is kind of a
form of that
um it's supposed to be learning from
your peers but
i think you know when you're an adult
for the most part even your mentors
still appear
well i guess what i'm saying is that the
community and the paragongy is like one
quarter of the whole thing that's not
even the main thing the main thing we're
doing
is we're taking each of these like
fragments and turning them into a
sentence so right now we're just focused
are you seeing the screen right now
so bentley are are you seeing this well
i just
think i mean we could either have four
sentences or we could have
one or two i just didn't think we'd need
one for each we can expand them out and
then shrink them back down
well i think like we're expanding them
out so that we can say like
what are we doing with the knowledge
commons
are we creating it are we are we selling
it are we
trying to destroy it what are we doing
with it
yeah and it's to me like the expanding
the adjacent possible is basically the
entire mission it's just not
as um what does that mean it means
building the community
to include the next group it means
building the resources so we have more
access to information that you know like
we don't have to each
do the same research again and again and
again like it's it's building it out
from where it's at
right so right we can't recreate wiki
wiki collection we can't recreate
wikipedia
but we can you know maybe create a
article right like there's something
that is is from exactly where we are
without
like visioning the big beautiful
but like where do what do we do now
without necessarily having that bridge
to get from here to there what is the
next adjacent possibility is impossible
right uh raymond i have a question about
i guess all of this
which i guess is like how
long term are these supposed to be this
supposed to be like just to get started
is this supposed to be something that
the vision and mission wouldn't change
throughout the entire course of the
organization
what is the yeah i'd say the goal is
is really yeah come up with something
that's not going to change
easily or soon right um a world where
abundant resources are available to
promote
projects so how long does that take to
create that for that world to be real
um that's the time frame um
right but like so if that's the vision
then sort of the
the mission should all go towards that
and that should be in theory the vision
of the organization the entire time that
exists so it's like it's meant to be
sort of as future
as as future proof as possible yeah
that's the goal
you know okay yeah and then you know uh
one of the
one of the things i've i've seen happen
in my experience and that
you know protocol that love doing this
work um has helped to
to design is when we notice that we're
coming to a place sometimes where
decisions are getting dicey where
there's like
um you're getting close like there's
there's like kind of 50 50 kind of 50
50. you want to do one thing
are we are we actually diverging in
mission here which is a perfect
opportunity to say
let's read the mission statement which
which decision is mostly in line with
the mission
yeah but i really want to do this well
hey maybe there's just a
maybe this cell is going to divide now
and we're going to have two
organizations with slightly different
missions that can work right in
conjunction with each other like
this is the kind of thing that this this
uh whole protocol dot love is designed
to help
ease you know right okay um because i
will say
personally one i think of together check
one of my main goals i think to start
with because
together tech has no money and no you
know almost anything it's really just
about
sort of being that community and
starting to provide some information you
know maybe some like
a group of test cases but long term i
kind of want it to be
like a game b multinational conglomerate
where like it can be the home for any of
these projects whether they're like you
know sort of pure game b
you know world changing or world saving
or just a for-profit project that's okay
with you know
all or most of his profit going towards
that organization
and not paying out anyone the
you know the profit shares
um but that is like there's a million
steps in between here and there
right um right and that's yeah so
definitely but that's where you want
that's what you want to be writing
not the million steps but to the there
what's the there
yeah okay so like this is the end state
what are all the things that we want to
do and so
if it's something that moves us towards
the creating a global network of blank
then that's good or if it's something
that you know builds that community or
builds the knowledge commons or any
other things that we're saying are the
mission statement
and then going back to you know for
three years down the road and talking
about board decisions we go back to the
mission statement and vision and say
you know this thing that we're talking
about how does that compare to
the mission does it help further any of
them does it hurt any of them
yeah okay yeah and definitely in terms
of breaking down like if you start
finding yourselves getting specific
about how to accomplish the mission
don't don't waste the energy just put it
down in the um
write it down while you're while it's
hot in the initial team accountability
section
right okay i mean like
i think we still have a difficulty with
the actual mission of like the vision
is the the abundant resources for anyone
who has a project right if the project
they think it's omni-win everyone else
thinks it's omni-win how did they how do
we help them facilitate creating it so
we have the projects in the world
we're also project holders so we come to
the table
with those two hats on i'm here
representing jubilee in jubilee's world
and i'm here representing solution
raising possibly too like i don't want
it to go away
but the bigger thing is for together
tech right so it's like okay am i here
is my vote because it's going to hurt my
project it's going to hurt me or it's
going to better the world right and
that's kind of going back to the mission
is okay maybe something that together
tech does hurts reasons for a wiki
election
but the bigger thing is the vision of
mission right the bigger
thing is is this going to help future
projects and is this going to help that
like bigger
so that we have more um resources
together
and there's a specific way because the
idea of creating a global net
the huge big game b thing right there's
um
a few projects that are looking to do
that and it feels like if that's
like holding that as the mission breaks
it
if that makes sense it's like that we
want to get so big
keeps us from doing the next adjacent
possible to actually get there because
we're so focused on is this going to get
us to the huge beautiful world
but it's like right but as a building
camaraderie right now like the four of
us
it keeps showing up again and again how
do we
invite more people to it that works and
i think we've talked about that enough
that like honestly it's not even on us
it's like we've created this space
if someone comes in and they don't feel
comfortable because they're not part of
a community
that's a different thing we can deal
with but i don't know i think i'm just
rambling on at this moment but
yes having that as the big mission could
hurt it
because it's like well wait that are we
working for together tech are we working
for individual projects and we're very
much in the tension of all and not all
of that
right i'm here for my project i'm here
for me and i'm here for the world
and i have to deal with where that fits
and the mission and vision how is like
about
we can keep bringing it back to that
right oh yes you're right i'm hurting
jubilee but i still want to vote for it
right like i still
yeah i'm hurting so
uh in other words okay um
so for instance this mission a world
where abundant resources are available
to pro omni-wind projects
like you could say that's the mission of
protocol.love too
right you could say that's the mission
of um the thing we were talking about
earlier today jubilee lake there's
probably so that's
and that's okay there's nothing wrong
with that's great that a whole a whole
bunch of different groups of people
would have
the same exact vision um so mission and
how they accomplish that
um hopefully that's where we get some
divergence right
hopefully the mission of how to
accomplish that with this group is
slightly different than the mission of
how to accomplish that from this group
so that you can
eventually hope for some synergistic um
results happening so
um like together tech i mean the name
to me sounds like technology to bring
people together uh to help them more
cohesively collaborate
so like i'm just throwing that out there
like but
just in tuning from all the things i'm
hearing but you know to try to create
simple and clear mission statement
um which is i think i think there's
something from what raymond is saying
like it's not about the big utopian idea
it's about the path to get there and
what makes us
different and that is the the expanding
the adjacent possible
it's hard to necessarily understand that
that is the that is the path it's like
right we don't take
we don't lay down 10 steps and then get
to this beautiful future because
everyone else is trying to do that and
it doesn't work because it's like
wait right left it's like there's just
too many iterations and too many things
and you're never getting that big
beautiful idea
but how we get there if we're
continually looking at the adjacent
possible and looking because we don't
have the resources to create
the technology that brings people
together at the moment or we would be
focusing on that instead of our
individual projects this is about how do
we
hold our individual projects and come
together to create omnium solutions
so until there's you know what i mean
like it's it's
like the path is in that tension like
it's that we're here as project holders
and creating omni when
solutions and playing in that tension
between our projects and the bigger
project but
isn't the path just the tactics that we
use to get there
like the whole expanding djs impossible
just sounds like that's a you know
our tactic or our strategy of okay we
know
our big grand ideal that we're trying to
go towards
there's an infinite number of things
that we theoretically could do to maybe
go towards that
but what can we do right now and then
once that happens what can we do then
and then then and then
and so it's always about taking that
next step so it's uh
you know a a tactic but towards what
because you could expand the adjacent
possible towards anything
yeah towards the vision right so the
question isn't is this
is this advancing solution raising is
this advancing jubilee as much as i'm
gonna wear both
of those hats it is is this advancing
together a tech is this creating omni
wind resource
solutions for all projects instead of
just my own
right is this gonna in you know like
there's that
it's not needing to plan out the entire
adjacent possible
right because it's like we try this it
fails it succeeds it is just about
continually trying the adjacent possible
and trying it
right not even like that's part of when
you plan a whole thing out and this
step three requires step one and two to
go according to plan
one and two never go according to plan
so it's like constantly being
what could we what do we want and what
can we do to get there now right with
and we love the big utopian idea we
every conversation
so jubilee i would say that expanding
the adjacent possible is a process
and not it's not specific enough for the
mission
and i know we can't lay out the whole
path
but i think for now even though we want
the mission to be long-term
i mean right now our our mission really
is just to
you know the vision is resources
and in this case i think we just need to
list out
and say what resources we're going to
start building
to be specific right so that our mission
becomes profitable will be how we
build on top of that and so we could
list that as a reminder saying this is
the process we're going to use to evolve
our mission as we go forward
um but in this case it's it's not like a
normal company where the vision is that
much different from the
from the mission ours are pretty close
because
our mission is specifically undefined
because it's whatever the community
needs
um because we have a wider scope
than than most businesses
so it sounds like our vision is the same
a world where abundant resources are
available for pro uneven projects
our mission is to be the organization
that provides those
those resources and then what we've
listed in the mission are the resources
that we're currently planning to provide
yeah and that was similarly nota that
like the resources are the community the
information and the technology
all of which we have some of and we
continue to grow it and then it is well
how do we grow that right and then it is
going back to the vision of mission
and is this helpful to my project is it
helpful that your project is helpful to
me is this on you know
all of all of that stuff yeah so i mean
i think it's as simple as
i mean at least it sounds simple so
you want your vision is a world where
abundant resources are available to pro
omni wind projects so
each of you just say so how do you
create a
a world where abundant resources are
available to pro omnimoon projects
if each of you answered that how do you
do that
hopefully we'd get some mission juices
flowing
okay and i think that's like that's my
understanding of what
this part is so what i just i i mean
here's my stab
at doing it so saying the main mission
is to provide
abundant resources to prom to promote
when projects
and then these are the things that we're
currently talking about doing
this can change this might end up going
somewhere else we're like here's what we
think
that that we can or should do but it all
goes towards this
so like the overall thing is our vision
is a world
even if we're not the ones to do it as
long as it happens awesome
but as long as we're talking about an
organization right that's where this is
breaking down
no we're talking about you guys are the
ones to do it and i think that's what's
missing
is the the the willingness to to make a
declaration
that we're going to do it and this is
how we're going to do it i think that's
what's missing right now right
sorry i thought that a vision statement
was kind of supposed to start
like general like a world where or is
a vision is we're doing this thing
the vision is a word where okay
and then the mission i shouldn't even
have written this because i was just
trying to play along with um
what uh that was me
okay uh yeah you were saying so i just
rewrote i potentially rewrote the vision
as a mission statement which is
it didn't help the pro it didn't help um
so the question is how do you provide
abundant resources to pro omni-1
projects
how do you do it now the how does that
go in the mission statement because i
thought
that seems like the thing that we would
always be adjusting and
you know if we want to provide a
community okay so what does that mean oh
turns out we just got this new you know
experts and you know whatever that looks
like correct
but the big big ones like how do you do
it
because like you you got to declare
something
or what or you know how can you how can
you enroll people to come join this
mission
if you don't know what they're doing
like how do you do
right you know what i'm saying right so
what's
different what we're doing
than this is that
i guess i'm trying to see where the
disconnect is because if we're saying
that this
well we probably want to you know change
the wording of it so it's not just
an obvious restate of the vision if the
goal is to figure out what
we're playing in all this i think it's
that
yeah i think
okay i don't think restating that in any
other way is going to help
what is um
uh so ray when we say build a knowledge
base
why is that not a mission statement
where does it say that
well we had knowledge base listed in
there so we had builder knowledge base
organization created an organization for
i mean and then do piragi you know
schedule meetings and stuff like that
those were
our three mission statements to build a
knowledge base is definitely a mission
statement um
but i don't see that so i don't know
where it went that's what we had listed
we had four things listed
they weren't sentences but they weren't
yeah i just want to clarify too
this is certainly not my expertise like
this part of it
like the mission vision is supposed to
be something that you guys can work out
as a team and then i'm gonna i
like the whole like like magic of what
i'm proposing is after we have this
clear and
like anything i'm doing here is
something anybody any outsider could
probably come into your group and do
just to clarify i'm
bringing no super expertise to the table
here so so forgive me if i'm fumbling
and bumbling too
but i would say yes to build the
knowledge base is definitely
something as an outsider i get some
grasp of what you're talking about now
yeah i think having those or those those
build the knowledge base
build the community i don't know what
the other things were the funding
right the actual the actual resources
the knowledge
the funding the people and the knowledge
base are basically
what we are building everything we do
are we
is it one of those three things and then
the adjacent possible is like right but
we don't have the money and the people
in the room to do it so it's like we're
showing up for round tables right we're
doing it within our current means for it
and within it who create round tables
right that's that's
community like to create community i
think if we had a better way to create
community we would be doing that instead
of round tables but
okay
who hosts weekly meetings i mean you're
doing you're already doing that is this
part of what this is
to host weekly meetings
towards building community though
because if we find that you know the
whole day weekly meetings isn't working
we might scrap that
but we're probably never going to scrap
building a community that's always going
to be a thing
we might cycle through tactics to do
that that's mine which is why i think
that having our mission be
our vision is the omni win the bigger
world beautiful and i think it's better
that we don't care if we're the ones who
do it
because we're very much in right there's
competitors in this space and if they
get there first
awesome we are doing ours the best we
can we're one of the people there
doing that and then it's like okay well
what we're doing that is the commons
that is
what what that omni-wind solution is is
the knowledge is the resources
is the um knowledge the resources and
the
technology whatever the other thing the
other one was people the knowledge the
resources
and um having it like that like having
it as
because it's like what we said
roundtables gets us closer to community
within our current system
it's the best we have currently that we
can do and show up to the people
we show up to so it's i think it is good
to have it
more generic that we can say okay what
are we doing for community what are we
doing for knowledge
to host um
conversations for people to discuss
the next adjacent possible step right
that would be something
so how specific are the missions
supposed to be because i'm like it seems
like the things that you're hearing
are the things that you that you're
suggesting i would think are tactics
towards it so i'm trying to i guess
figure out like
the difference in saying just something
kind of
intentionally vague like building a
community versus
whole weekly meetings and you know um do
the project round tables and and send
out
a monthly newsletter and all the
individual steps that we think might
help
build the community or are we just
saying
build a community and then maybe here's
just some of the elements that
it will probably have like at the high
level like mentorship and you know
so the object to answer that question we
have to go to the objective of what
we're trying to do with this document
which since it's my template i i'll
answer that from that perspective
um the vision is that grand
vague thing right have to be as vague as
you want with the vision
mission the goal is to have somebody
read the mission
and go oh i've always wanted to do that
thing
this is the place for me okay and then
then if you want when you get more
detailed
that's in the team accountabilities like
actually what
like what could i do right now to start
moving the mission forward that's kind
of like an accountability
like a very specific item right and i
even that could be 10 levels deep
right but so that's it so the vision is
totally vague on purpose
the mission is to something somebody can
read and find that they're in alignment
very quickly and easily and it's initial
team accountability is the breakdown of
really the deep the detailed how
to accomplish a mission right like has
to get this has to get them this has to
get done right
so things like holding a weekly meeting
with those being
the the initial team accountabilities
because we're saying like yeah
you need to do this in order to help you
know accomplish this certain mission
right so that's where i went to more
like two whole conversations
right more generic than weekly meeting
right two whole conversations
right and then then yeah initial key to
team accountability would be
schedule weekly meeting each week that
would be an accountability right
so to hold conversations maybe something
that belongs in the mission if i'm
hearing correct
to create space for conversations to
happen even right
maybe it'd be easier to start with the
more concrete things that we know rather
than the more fuzzy ones
like have we already maybe it's already
up there but
i guess we have a lot of writing up
there now so
we have knowledge commons did we just
want to put that in a you know create
and maintain a knowledge commons for
omni-wind projects there we go that's
more concrete
or do you already feel like what we have
is already good
i guess i i'm having trouble following
the document maybe we should
turn everything in a gray color that was
just
brainstorming yeah we're deleted it's in
the hist it's in the google history you
know
well then we need
i guess i don't know which which of
these things on the screen are
current
yeah i liked it how it was before how we
were just it was um
partially grayed out so we could still
see it and see where the brainstorming
was that was a little more brain
like it wasn't all of our brainstorming
right it wasn't every idea but it was a
little more
down how we how we had it um yeah like
that
like that this section i think i had we
had cleaned out some of the gray but
yeah like the vision has that
a world where exactly it's the knowledge
commons which is i don't know if we're
quite
i guess that's hard because we're i
think we're still in brainstorming mode
so we're not quite sure what's going on
i think this is the reason why we were
going like to go on to the currency i
feel like is going to help i know
that this is in a specific way but the
reason is like what we have to begin
with is
really our mission to keep doing the
adjacent possible because as beautiful
as the common knowledge is we don't
you guys are already working on your
projects that are about common knowledge
right
you're not going to stop that and we're
going to create a wiki for game b
projects it's just not going to happen
so what we're doing is the community
like that's like what is the adjacent
possible then as we're collecting
information yes we might add it to a
database or might do that
but that's not really our focus so until
that's our focus
it seems you know what i mean like
counterintuitive the idea is to keep
creating adjacent possible solutions
that
bringing us more community bringing us
more knowledge bringing us more
resources
and do we have more you know this year
than we did last year more this month
than we did last month
and looking at those those metrics do we
feel our projects are further on than
they were before before we have this
connection
i do even though i start new projects
every week
i'm further on my own project so
well i thought one of the reasons we
were kind of bringing this all together
is because we decided we were going to
start to try and do some crowd funding
okay yeah that's
so maybe if that is our if that's our
purpose for this then like
what
like this feels more like grant writing
then where it's like well what is our
first
um what is it we're putting crowdfunding
towards because that should be kind of
what we're tailoring this towards right
like is it the information database
we're asking people to fund and then
we'll put that together
like what is it the mentorship is it the
round tables like what is it we're
actually looking for funding on
um if that is why we're doing this i
know like
yeah personally i think it's a bit too
early for funding i think we build the
community first and then we'll set some
sort of a threshold for like you know
once we have i don't know a thousand
followers or you know 10 people watching
the live streams or
just at least some number to say like
okay we've got an audience
because unless we're planning on like
spending money and unless we're really
confident in the messaging
for the crowdfunding campaign i mean
i've only done one but like
it was really hard to do it with without
an audience
because then you you know it's really
down to like your marketing
and your ability to hook people in like
a single sentence
which you know we've been talking now
for about 35 minutes
and we're still like sort of not quite
sure what it is that we're doing
i think it's when we have an audience
and we have the a specific obvious
you know in next step the adjacent
possibles he seems to be x and we need
money to do that
and we have an audience that we can
speak to we we don't have to reinvent
the wheel
to you know to tell them that story i
think that's our first attempt at at
crowdfunding
okay but if it sounded that was very
definitive there will be a crowdfunding
campaign so that was good
once we have the audience once the
audience is there right so that is the
like we're we're playing in the adjacent
possible even in this conversation we're
playing in the adjacent possible
that is still our mission it's like what
is the next little thing we can do that
gets us closer to that vision
that is within our ability to do i think
that is our mission like it's like
what is the next thing that gets us
community resources or information
that we are capable of but isn't that
true for every project
that you always want to take your next
step i sent you guys the the the
document
that got that the gifted consultations
document right
and so perhaps all we're dealing with is
the fact that you're not actually ready
to do a document right now
like like i just try to identify in that
document i say there's three basic
phases you go in
um phase one people have come together
by some attraction field
they're in conversation with each other
and it starts to feel like there's
something to be done
like it seems like where you're at
that's phase one it starts to feel like
there's something to be done but you're
not exactly sure what yet it really
it doesn't right so phase two is
discussion begins to revolve around
something more specific
there's more direction and specifics in
the speech an idea for a vision and or
mission
begins to form so you're kind of in
there
but not so you're kind of between phase
one and phase two i mean the time to
start
the document is definitely when you're
in phase two when you're starting to get
some clarity
around what exactly you're gonna do and
i feel like it sounds like we don't have
clarity but we really do have clarity
like it's like what we are doing is that
adjacent possible i know that sounds
very big and anyone reading that can be
slightly vague but it's already what
we're doing it's already what we've been
doing for six months to a year
is you know that adjacent possible piece
and part of the reason we're doing this
is we didn't we don't quite understand
what is together text umbrella and what
is like
a you know wiki election we know that's
adriel's but like this new thing that's
possibly being created is that part of
together tech is it is it
separate and so it is coming together
and kind of working
through the fuzziness so we have that
and that's where like we've spent a few
weeks on the vision of mission i don't
think we're gonna get any more clarity
i think it is about going on to the
currency and going on to
to what does what does the rest of this
look like even with the fuzziness
because i think we aren't actually as
fuzzy as it seems we're just fuzzy in a
game a
sense because it needs a very game a
this is the blueprint you don't start
building until you have the blueprint
and we're very much in the
yeah we have a blueprint for our own
projects and we're working through that
and we're also just doing the adjacent
possible because we don't have the
resources and we don't have the
we don't have the vision and so the
mission's like
a little bit closer a little bit closer
are we meeting are we are we getting
closer what is the next little thing we
can do as it arises
okay uh
so yeah i guess there's no so i mean i'm
i'm anxious to move on too because again
this isn't really anything where i
provide any special expertise or insight
i mean
if you guys know what you're trying to
do together or you don't
uh so i heard but i heard so much in
there um so
you know that you want to do this
thing but you you have gone as far as
identifying a name together tech
and so it seems like if you're going to
come together under a name that you
could
define why you
are coming together under that name at
minimum
and it does sound like it's as generic
as to create a space for conversations
to happen around
identifying the next adjacent possible
so we could we kind of go with that
perhaps and
i think that actually works create
conversations around the next adjacent
possible because that is what we are
doing and it's like can we
take this on yet can we take it on can
we take it off the next adjacent
possible
could be about anything but we're
specifically the next adjacent possible
for
omni-wind projects yeah right
totally because that's your vision so
that's kind of inherent
so this is not technology to bring
people together this is technology that
people build together to accomplish
things
it's not to bring people together yes if
we build together and own together so
yes okay there we go we're getting
somewhere
is a uh omni win
uh owned together built together owned
together is that somewhere anywhere
i don't think so um
create a sense
build that's good that's got to be
somewhere because that was clear
and i i mean my understanding is that
that's kind of going to be
a subset like you know if bentley
decides to build reason score entirely
on his own
and own it but it's still like you know
going towards the
the mission i think he can still be a
part of to together tech
ideally i think that we want to get to
the point where really important
technologies are owned by
the cooperative that's my understanding
right but that's why he owns together
like that's why he that's why we're here
is because we don't want to give up our
projects yet we don't want
it like and so recent score isn't part
of together tech unless it is part of
together tech right so that is
once someone's ready to give it up and
start that is the point otherwise it's
theirs and they're just part of the
community and that's fine it's like
playing in that but if we create some
this is about creating something
together that isn't any of those
individual ones
but helps those individual ones and that
already it already is
ours right if we create something and
then it's like oh but just the four of
us own it
then it's just another project that the
four of us own that isn't together tech
right like it's there's something about
it is the commons like it is something
we own together
that is we created together now there
could be percentages right so
and i don't what i don't know but that
yes owning it together and building it
together is part of
part of what we are we are doing all
right
it does seem like it could be a simple
and clear-cut the mission
in its entirety could be to create space
for conversations to happen around
identifying the next adjacent possible
and providing abundant resources to pro
omni wind projects
that could be important that could be
exactly what you guys are doing that
makes sense i understand that
like that something somebody can read
and say okay i get what you're doing now
all right so should we bold that i don't
i don't have the ability to
to do there we go all right
so all right that's our mission 45
minutes in we did it we did it after a
few weeks
and i got to go in 15 of course but uh
should i plan for more than an hour if i
should have i'm sorry i don't know our
hour
it's an hour we're gonna just wait for
an hour and then move on to the
the next week that's kind of what we're
what we're doing and then the next week
whatever we
finish we start the next week okay so
the next section to really grok it is a
combination of
like understanding um what an influence
currency is
um and understanding what you're at
and assets and decision making so it's
kind of like
like you kind of have to kind of hold
all these in your brain at the same time
influence currency is the number of
votes one would have to say
in um a proposal regarding the
stewardship of assets
so we have to steward something like
um is there a domain name are there some
google docs are there like these are
things that these are assets that
probably exist so we can start listing
those things
and then um we can also determine like
how have you guys been doing it the
object with decision making and
influence currency is not to
invent the perfect governance model
which is something this group
could spend the next 10 years doing
well i'm sure um but the outside the
object is not to
create the the ultimate governance model
but the object is to look at what's been
working
it keeps you guys coming back to these
meetings together and slowly
nudging things forward like how has that
process been working have you been in
just full consensus about things has
somebody kind of just
taken the rain most of the time and made
things happen and then everybody else
said yeah that's cool after the fact
like like looking at those kind of
things and that all kind of flows into
are we all having equal influence
currency are we out doing everything
actually by consensus or is there
somebody that's
that's holding a lot more influence
currency this is just kind of the
influential one that we
that we the rest of us are riding along
with and providing feedback for
and then what is the actual thing that
we want has been happening
and that we can maybe put the slight
amount of formality on
to when decisions are getting made like
we've just been getting together each
week
talking about stuff and then saying yes
and then that happens
if that's the case let's write that down
for the most part and then perhaps
recommending that one more formal
process to just document the fact that
you
did in fact have a proposal and resolve
that proposal successfully to where you
all agreed that that's what should
happen
just like a slight amount of formality
to it hope all that made sense
um any thoughts
on how you were doing it it's like how
are we doing it
um i think what you we have just been
getting together for conversations
and um we spend an hour
on together tech on the omni wind
solution whatever that looks like we're
doing it every other week and now we're
doing it every week we have something to
actually do
um which is this the foundational
document and
um then we get together for round tables
on saturdays
that is what we have been doing the
assets i would say are
are um that that are hour a week but
also um
the stream yard we're on is is part of
uh under wiki election but that
i have the togethertech.org which i did
just renew
for 30 bucks for the year um
let's get that one down together
to together tk
yep sorry sorry sorry tec i don't know
why i said yes decay
is yeah org um domain name and website
do we say
uh yeah the website's not so great at
the moment but mainly just domain name
okay still my vision from like a year
well
if you wanted to make changes to that
website
do you want to be able to just do that
on your own or would you be
coming back to the group to say hey this
is our like we steward this website
together
i'm not going to make changes without
full approval of this group but through
our decision-making methodology that we
establish here
i think it's basically i mean right now
like i said it's my mission my vision
for old together tech up there
i am down with anyone changing it and
having it be more of what together tech
is actually doing right now
i can't change it i just can't that's
not within my wheelhouse so
but i think we would want whoever is
changing it to check with the group
okay i think there's also the facebook
group it's probably another asset
yes well we could
um there's usually a number facebook
gives you can grab
um it's actually called uh together tech
because it's
groups together tech it's the groupie
project game b
projects is together tech is what what
is that what you mean
yeah it's yeah i did someone else want
to grab the url because i'm not gonna be
able to i'm not gonna be able to copy
and paste but it's like backslash groups
backslash
solution not solution racing together
attack is the name of it
solution raising together tech i might
be able to actually do it now that i'm
thinking about it because
i just stuck it in there okay cool
and there's also the youtube channel let
me grab that
oh yes look at us assets
okay so now in general anything listed
here we understand we're going to use
some
uh decision-making methodology approval
by the group
over any changes to these assets any
anything that happens to these assets
how that exactly looks we get to
determine so
i'll get caught up in that for now um
but the fact is as opposed to this is
mine i can do what i want with it
we're saying these are things that we
recognize as shared assets that we're
not going to do anything without
going through the collective
merely by writing it here we're saying
that sounds good
cool so um
how do you think you've been just
generally making decisions so far has
just been
probably informal consensus that's what
i'm feeling yeah we've been showing up
to this meeting and then whenever we
have a
uh agenda which we honestly don't even
fill out anymore that is like if
something comes up you put it on the
agenda and then we talk about joints
time like
the togethertech.org renewal was coming
up and i was like should i keep it or
should i get rid of it and we decided to
keep it and figured i didn't have to
host it anyway so that
okay it's part of a verbal conversation
is basically what we've been
we've been doing yeah which basically is
informal consensus
right cool so um
[Music]
this is a slightly older version of the
template you guys use and there's been a
bunch of updates but
basically what we can do is list your
names and
an influence currency amount which
sounds like it's probably been
the same like everybody has had
equal influence
yeah i think we can do equal splits
right now
yeah and then i i use 111 you can really
you could be
eight it could be you know it could be
any number if it's the same number then
it's equal influence right
so you guys just want to list your names
and put 111 you can do that or change
the number to whatever you want
keep it the same and i have a hundred
percent of the vote i'm gonna
rule over everything yeah right now
jubilee's got it all because that's the
only name on there
um i don't get access to the dog so
i didn't even see my name was spelt
wrong i love it i was like
yeah there we go
it's also it's spelt up at the top his
name
radic's name yeah that one
okay awesome um so one of the other
things that it's really nice to be
transparent about at this time
right for the shared intentions of
omni-win
is if somebody else found out what you
guys are up to and
loved it and wanted to be part of it
what would how would they do that how
would they get influenced and say hey i
want to
i like what you're doing with that
website i think i have
would want to steward it too help
steward that website how would they
ultimately gain any influence over that
website
so the current process i think would be
they would join the facebook group and
show up to one of our
our friday meetings
there we go so we should write this um
join that facebook group
go up to a friday meeting
so it's actually a little it's like keep
showing up to friday meetings that's our
only like come to three of them and
you're basically on the board
you might want to specifically say board
meetings show up to our to a yeah
friday board meetings yeah because we do
something else
yeah so one thing actually one thing
that's in them um
so we'll what what i'm gonna i'm gonna
call this
the primary or we could call the board
if you want but generally i call it the
primary council
we can totally call it whatever you want
it's totally up to you um
and uh then there's so that exists to
steward
um this is one of the adjustments in the
new template which is pretty crucial
so i go
councils i'm gonna go primary
council
um description
two words of all
assets listed
okay so that's the job of the primary
council and the primary council in order
to make decisions has to have influence
currency in the protocol.love ontology
you have to have influence currency in
order to
steward make decisions and you have to
make decisions in order to steward
assets
um so
um keep showing up to friday meetings
then what would happen
would one of you eventually say hey i
think this person should have influence
currency and i think that is where we
have
in no way done this yet because it has
just been that simple like
you know like someone just keeps showing
up and if there's someone to keep
showing up they either fall off
they they stay but yes that i think that
aside from the four of us it might be
helpful to have an
actual vote right as this person if
someone shows up and continually
as actually like a carry came right and
is continually showing up and
taking on action that's very different
than someone showing up and just telling
us what to do
that there is like a
okay well i mean you can vote on it yeah
you will see
you could totally do that right somebody
says hey this person's been showing up i
think we want to give them influence
or you could just say every time you
show up for a meeting you earn
one influence currency i mean whatever
you guys are into
what feels right to everyone else i mean
i feel like yeah if we're at i mean 111
it's a weird number to be out but we
keep showing up um
i also don't feel like you know what i
mean if bentley can't make it one week
around i can't make them on week that
we're taking theirs away and then i get
it because i show up
but like up to a maximum of 100 that if
yeah you have to show up to 20 in order
to get up to that right you get five per
something like that might be helpful but
it also
i like math so maybe it's just because i
like math
yeah i kind of doubt that we'd actually
keep that up to date personally
so we'll vote against it solely for that
reason
okay cool so it could just be um
so they keep showing up i'd say they
have to go to three how does three sound
and then after they've been to three we
can put up for a vote
do we say this person's still on board
and then they get equal rights
right they would become 120th one-fifth
well
20 is what i was trying to say of it if
we voted them in right and that would be
kind of how it
it goes from there ask them if they want
to be part of it
if they show up to three and they want
to be part of it then we vote on
yes another option which i think might
be available given that we've listed out
councils is to kind of almost have like
a secondary council or
you know i don't know like it's kind of
meant to have
some amount of voting and this and that
and people start there
and then if you know they show up and
they actually make votes and you know
they contribute in that way
then at some point that they can join
the primary council
there you go stuff like that so you can
think about that
um because the other thing is you can
you can have a separate currency right
this is the primary council influence
currency but you can just have
what we would generally consider an
equity currency just because it's a co
equity i'm doing this the really fast
version because we're out of time
but equity it just represents
contribution for lack of
more time to explain deeper so you could
just create an equity currency that you
get one
you get one of these currencies every
time you show up to a meeting which is
does not give you influence inherently
but we are still recognizing you
and then later on you can say hey
anybody with this earned x-men
equity currency we're going to convert
it to x amount of influence currency or
whatever
um but these things give us the building
blocks for like
to follow this specification of defining
these things that developers can come in
and
like write this code for you
lickety-split because it's all part of
like this grand framework and there's
you know all the
expertise available to work within that
framework
i think this is a good place like you
said you're at the time for us to end
here and kind of sit with this over the
next week that like yes
is this what because if we vote no we
don't want this person on what happens
to them are they not here or they
is there that secondary council is it
just they don't have this is it
so anyway sitting with that and coming
next time with the ideas of
how could this work how could someone
join us on the council could there be a
secondary option
do they need to attend three times
before like is there tears to this and
what do those tears look like
well i don't think we'll have a
definitive answer we show up because we
haven't had a conversation but
having that be what we do between now
and next week does that sound good to
everyone
i'm gonna go with bentley said yes
because i can't okay let's say goodbye
to youtube so
raymond can get going and thank you
raymond for joining us as well
goodbye